Michael B. James

Research Interests I am interested in Program Synthesis and Language Design. I think of Programming Languages as an interface to express intent. I want to build systems and tools to help programmers, expert and novice alike, complete their task faster and safer.

Education University of California, San Diego

Ph.D., Computer Science, 2018-present.

Advisor: Nadia Polikarpova

Fields: Programming Languages, Program Synthesis

Tufts University

B.S., Computer Science, 2015.

Experience

Software Engineer II

Jana Mobile, Boston, Massachusetts, Feb 2017 - Jun 2018

2018 Created mobile anti-fraud mechanisms and data collection streams

2017 managed data scientists' data collection APIs

Software Engineer I

Uber Technologies, San Francisco, Jul 2015 - Dec 2016

2016 Lead team migration to golang, through anti-fraud miroservice

Owned business.uber.com. Migrated to React, using FRP styles 2015

Elm Intern

Prezi, Budapest, Hungary, Summer 2014

Mentor: Evan Czaplicki

Built interactive, time-traveling debugger for Elm-lang.

Publications

Program Synthesis by Type-Guided Abstraction Refinement. Zheng Guo, Michael James, David Justo, Jiaxiao Zhou, Ziteng Wang, Ranjit Jhala, Nadia Polikarpova 47th ACM SIGPLAN Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages (POPL 2020). January 2020.

Teaching

Graduate Teaching Assistant

UC San Diego, Fall 2019

Supervisor: Nadia Polikarpova

Course: undergraduate intro-to-programming languages course.

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Tufts University, Fall 2014 Supervisor: Kathleen Fisher

Course: undergraduate intro-to-programming-languages

Talks

2019 Component-based Type Driven Synthesis

Location: University of California, San Diego